Quyen Lynch

Experienced English Language Arts teacher with 12 years of instructional leadership at the classroom, school site, and district levels. Challenges students with engaging lessons designed to help them meet the language and skill demands of the 21st century. Experienced with diverse student populations. Builds rapport with students and their families to support students' self-efficacy.

qhoang4@gmail.com

- **(714) 454-3149**
- Orange County, CA

EXPERIENCE

ELA, AVID, and Study Skills Teacher, Grades 7-8 Louis Lake Intermediate School Garden Grove, CA - Garden Grove Unified School District

September 2007 - October 2012; September 2015 - Present

- Achieved 82% student pass rate on California Smarter Balanced Assessment for Grade 7 Language Arts in 2018-19
- Analyzed student data in conjunction with state and district assessments to impact student achievement by +15%
- Applied various instructional strategies and maintained high expectations to help all students meet and exceed grade-level standards
- Developed language aids through the ELA Department and Instructional Leadership Team for use in all content area classrooms
- Created advisement lessons to support district's Personal Skills goal
- Designed and coordinated Parent Education program to support families' socio-emotional needs
- Collaborated with other teacher-leaders to create instructional pacing guides for Grade 7, district-wide
- Spread positivity and practiced kindness with all staff and students

ELA & AVID Teacher, Grades 7-8 Dr. Walter C. Ralston Intermediate School Garden Grove, CA - Garden Grove Unified School District

October 2012 - June 2015

- Collaborated with Instructional Leadership Team on implementation of instructional technology in all subject areas
- Coordinated Advancement Via Individual Determination (AVID) program to foster academic success with underserved populations
- Upleveled original summary writing goal in AVID to include rhetorical analysis for non-fiction texts

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts, Literary Journalism University of California, Irvine - Irvine, CA

September 2002 - December 2005

CREDENTIALS

Single Subject Teaching Credential, CA — English Language Arts
Professional Education Permit: Residency Teacher, WA - English
Language Arts, English Language Learners

SKILLS

Data-driven lesson planning

Effective classroom management

Technological savvy

Excellent organization and time management skills

Adaptability to change

Collaborative mindset

Professional humility and intellectual risk taking

Servant-leadership

LEADERSHIP POSITIONS

ELA Department Chair

AVID Co-Coordinator

Parent Education Coordinator

No Place For Hate Committee

Faculty Advisory Committee

Instructional Leadership
Team

Social Committee Chair

DISTRICT INITIATIVES

Textbook Pilot, 2010 and 2015

Grading Consult

Writing Consult

UCI LiveInk Study Participant

Instructional Pacing Consult

Distance Learning Grading Committee